<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>Core</category>
  <title>View Controllers</title>
  <description><![CDATA[The View Controllers module provides access to nodes controlling multiple views within a single panel. A view is a display of data packed within layout. Slice Views and 3D Views are two types of views that can appear in a layout and whose controls can also be accessed from the View Controllers module. Each type of view has a separate section of the View Controllers panel. For example, the Slice Controllers are grouped together, followed by the 3D Controllers. An extra panel allows an alternative control over a Slice View.]]></description>
  <documentation-url>http://wiki.slicer.org/slicerWiki/index.php/Documentation/Nightly/Modules/ViewControllers</documentation-url>
  <license>slicer4</license>
  <contributor>Wendy Plesniak (SPL, BWH), Jim Miller (GE), Steve Pieper (Isomics), Ron Kikinis (SPL, BWH), Jean-Christophe Fillion-Robin (Kitware)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements><![CDATA[This work is part of the National Alliance for Medical Image Computing (NAMIC), funded by the National Institutes of Health through the NIH Roadmap for Medical Research, Grant U54 EB005149.]]></acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>Slice Controllers</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Slice Controllers for each of the Slice Views visible in the current layout. This is the same controller that is accessible from the bar at the top of a Slice View. It provides access to select the content (foreground, background, label) as well as control reformation, linking, visibility in the 3D view, lightbox, etc.]]></description>
  </parameters>
  <parameters>
    <label>3D View Controllers</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Controllers for each 3D View. This is the same controller that is accessible from the bar at the top of a 3D View. It provides access to the view direction, zooming, spinning, rocking, etc.]]></description>
  </parameters>
  <parameters>
    <label>Slice Information</label>
    <description><![CDATA[An alternative panel to control geometric parameters of a Slice View (field of view, lightbox, slice spacing).]]></description>
  </parameters>
</executable>
