<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>Registration.Specialized</category>
  <title>ACPC Transform</title>
  <index>1</index>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Calculate a transformation that aligns brain images to standard orientation based on anatomical landmarks.</p><p>The ACPC line extends between two points, one at the anterior commissure and one at the posterior commissure. The resulting transform will bring the line connecting the two points horizontal to the AP axis.</p><p>The midline is a series of points (at least 3) defining the division between the hemispheres of the brain (the mid sagittal plane). The resulting transform will result in the output volume having the mid sagittal plane lined up with the AS plane.</p><p>Use the Filtering module <b>Resample Scalar/Vector/DWI Volume</b> to apply the transformation to a volume.</p>]]></description>
  <version>1.0</version>
  <documentation-url>http://wiki.slicer.org/slicerWiki/index.php/Documentation/Nightly/Modules/ACPCTransform</documentation-url>
  <license>slicer3</license>
  <contributor>Nicole Aucoin (SPL, BWH), Ron Kikinis (SPL, BWH)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements><![CDATA[This work is part of the National Alliance for Medical Image Computing (NAMIC), funded by the National Institutes of Health through the NIH Roadmap for Medical Research, Grant U54 EB005149.]]></acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>Transform panel</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Calculate a transform from midline and ACPC fiducial lists.]]></description>
    <point multiple="true" coordinateSystem="ras">
      <name>ACPC</name>
      <label>ACPC Line</label>
      <longflag>--acpc</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[ACPC line, a list of two fiducial points, one at the anterior commissure and one at the posterior commissure.]]></description>
      <default>0,0,0</default>
    </point>
    <point multiple="true" coordinateSystem="ras">
      <name>Midline</name>
      <label>Midline</label>
      <longflag>--midline</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[The midline is a series of points (at least 3) defining the division between the hemispheres of the brain (the mid sagittal plane).]]></description>
      <default>0,0,0</default>
    </point>
    <transform fileExtensions=".txt">
      <name>OutputTransform</name>
      <longflag>--outputTransform</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[A transform filled in from the ACPC and Midline registration calculation.]]></description>
      <label>Output transform</label>
      <channel>output</channel>
    </transform>
  </parameters>
</executable>
